Eric Christine

Boulder, Colorado 80302 | 513-658-6378 | ericjchristine@gmail.com

Github | LinkedIn | Website

Full Stack Web Developer

Curious, collaborative, and coachable individual with a B.S. in Sustainability from The Ohio State University.

2021 bootcamp graduate from Flatiron School, specialized in full-stack software engineering.

Possess a creative skillset including Photoshop and Lightroom, with an emphasis on the end user experience. A strong background in sustainability brings transferable problem-solving and systems-thinking skills to any team or project.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, React Native, WordPress, Wix

Backend: Ruby On Rails, Firebase

Additional: Git, XCode, Swift, Adobe Lightroom, Adobe Photoshop, Elementor, SEO, Google Analytics, HostGator, Stripe

EXPERIENCE

Schwing Marketing Services

Web Developer

Denver, CO / Remote

03/2021 - Present

- Develop and optimize new and existing WordPress and Wix sites for their businesses, engage directly with clients
- Prioritize updates, decide which technologies work best for clients' needs.
- Developing and publishing several projects simultaneously in a remote-first environment.

Cycle Technology_

Miami, FL / Remote

01/2021 - Present

Software Engineer Intern

- Refreshed multiple pages on core website using new Wordpress plugins to replicate an Adobe XD design.
- Manage Google SEO, Wordpress Plugins, HTML iframes, and Content for a site that reaches 1900+ visits / month.

Tech Elevator

Columbus, OH

Puringer Development Intern

Business Development Intern

05/2019 - 08/2019

- Communicated closely with the Talent Acquisition Manager to find specific, top-talent for a rapidly growing company
- Enlisted over 30 new hiring partners to develop career opportunities for graduating Java & .NET development students.

Ohio State Student Life

Columbus, OH

Sustainability Student Lead

08/2018 - 05/2020

- Responsible for communicating with students through peer-to-peer tabling discussions, mentorship groups, and presentations.
- Consistently built Twitter, Facebook, and Instagram accounts to achieve the greatest reach and impact.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Siam Orchid Thai Restaurant - Github | Live Site

HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Website refresh for a small business

Utilized HTML, CSS, and Vanilla JavaScript to create a responsive desktop and mobile website.

Buckeye Recycle - Github | Demo

React Native, Ruby on Rails

Recycling mobile app that aims to gamify recycling and reduce waste on university campuses.

- Developed skills in React Native in 2 weeks to build full stack app from scratch
- Customized search bar to pull results across several parameters

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

Immersive Full Stack Web Software Engineering Program

Denver, CO Graduated 01/2021

The Ohio State University

Columbus, OH Graduated 05/2020

Bachelor's of Science in Environment, Economy, Development, & Sustainability (EEDS)